Guide to the Hudson River Day Line Records 1818-1949 MS 315
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Bound Volumes, circa 1833-1948; 52 Linear feet (375 bound volumes)
  - SS Mercury. Unpaid bills (Offsite-box HR-81, Volume SN-281)
  - Unidentified (Unpaid bills?) (Offsite-box HR-81, Volume SN-282)
  - Visitor's Register. Hudson-Fulton Celebration replica of "Clermont" (1 of 2), 1909 (Offsite-box HR-82, Volume SN-283)
  - Various steamboats, including Mary Powell. Summary of receipts, expenses, and passengers, 1860s-1875 (Offsite-box HR-82, Volume SN-284)
  - Accounts, 1865-1869 (Offsite-box HR-82, Volume SN-285)
  - Disbursements ledger, 1865 (Offsite-box HR-82, Volume SN-286)
  - New York returns, to September 1856 (Offsite-box HR-82, Volume SN-287)
    The volumes labeled "New York returns" appear to refer, not to accounts or reports concerning the steamboat New York, but to journal entries of disbursements made on a daily basis from the New York office.
  - New York returns, 1858 (Offsite-box HR-83, Volume SN-288)
  - Cash book, 1900-1901 (Offsite-box HR-83, Volume SN-289)
  - Daily & weekly earnings book (Offsite-box HR-83, Volume SN-290)
  - SS Chauncey Vibbard. Passage reports, 1865 (Offsite-box HR-83, Volume SN-291)
  - Towing, 1859-1861 (Offsite-box HR-83, Volume SN-292)
  - Visitor's Register. Hudson-Fulton Celebration replica of "Clermont" (2 of 2), 1911-1912 (Offsite-box HR-84, Volume SN-293)
  - New York returns, 1867 (Offsite-box HR-84, Volume SN-294)
  - Petty cash account, 1858-1868 (Offsite-box HR-84, Volume SN-295)
  - Classification of expenses and other financial data, 1857-1860 (Offsite-box HR-84, Volume SN-296)
  - New York returns, 1854-1855 (Offsite-box HR-84, Volume SN-297)
  - Permits (Offsite-box HR-85, Volume SN-298)
  - Unidentified (Offsite-box HR-85, Volume SN-298.1)
  - Coal shipping receipts from Delaware & Hudson Canal Company, 1867-1867 (Offsite-box HR-85, Volume SN-299)
  - Unidentified (Checkbook?) (Offsite-box HR-86, Volume SN-300)
  - Various steamboats. Passage book, 1856 (Offsite-box HR-85, Volume SN-301)
  - Accounts, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box HR-86, Volume SN-302)
  - New York returns, 1859 (Offsite-box HR-86, Volume SN-303)
  - New York returns, 1855 (Offsite-box HR-87, Volume SN-304)
  - New York returns, 1863 (Offsite-box HR-87, Volume SN-305)
  - New York returns, from September 1857 (Offsite-box HR-87, Volume SN-306)
  - Cash book B. V.B.G. & Co. (Offsite-box HR-87, Volume SN-307)
  - Unidentified (account book?) (Offsite-box HR-87, Volume SN-308)
  - Unidentified (Shipping receipts?) (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-309)
  - Unidentified (Receipts?) (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-310)
  - New York returns, from September 1856 (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-311)
  - New York returns, to September 1857 (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-312)
  - New York returns, 1864 (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-313)
  - Barge Washington. Passage book, 1854 (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-314)
  - Account book (Offsite-box HR-88, Volume SN-315)
  - Towing ledger, 1858 (Offsite-box HR-89, Volume SN-316)
  - Towing permits (Offsite-box HR-89, Volume SN-317)
  - Towing bills, 1850 (Offsite-box HR-89, Volume SN-318)
  - Towing ledger, 1855 (Offsite-box HR-90, Volume SN-319)
  - Towing ledger, 1857 (Offsite-box HR-90, Volume SN-320)
  - Downtows, 1856 (Offsite-box HR-90, Volume SN-321)
  - Downtows, 1862 (Offsite-box HR-90, Volume SN-322)
  - Downtows, 1855 (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-323)
  - New York returns, 1862 (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-324)
  - New York returns, 1861 (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-325)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-326)
  - Scrapbook. "The Launch of the Hendrick Hudson" (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-327)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-91, Volume SN-328)
  - Cash book, 1894-1899 (Offsite-box HR-92, Volume SN-329)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-92, Volume SN-330)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-92, Volume SN-331)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-92, Volume SN-332)
  - Evening record for Hudson River Day Line at Albany, 1914-1928 (Offsite-box HR-92, Volume SN-333)
  - Passenger report, 1945-1948 (Offsite-box HR-93, Volume SN-334)
  - Scrapbook* #35 (Offsite-box HR-93, Volume SN-335)
    A few scrapbooks in oversize 20th century binders were numbered as 33-41, with gaps. Several other unnumbered scrapbooks were in similar binders, suggesting that they were part of a set. Each of these were marked with an asterisk by the archivist in the container list.
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-336)
  - Recapitulation of passenger counts, receipts, expenses, 1901-1902 (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-337)
  - Minutes book. Mary Powell Steamboat Company, 1899-1918 (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-338)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-339)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-340)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-341)
  - Boilers. Hudson River Day Line (Offsite-box HR-94, Volume SN-342)
  - Check stubs. Mary Powell Steamship Company, 1913-1919 (Offsite-box HR-95, Volume SN-343)
  - New York returns, 1866 (Offsite-box HR-95, Volume SN-344)
  - New York returns, 1867? (Offsite-box HR-95, Volume SN-345)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-95, Volume SN-346)
  - Passengers received and landed, 1902-1915? (Offsite-box HR-96, Volume SN-347)
    Sequence numbers 347-349 are a set of volumes with date span of about 1902-1915 and possibly into the 1920s.
  - Passengers received and landed, 1902-1915? (Offsite-box HR-96, Volume SN-348)
  - Passengers received and landed, 1902-1915? (Offsite-box HR-96, Volume SN-349)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-96, Volume SN-350)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-97, Volume SN-351)
  - Scrapbook* #41 (Offsite-box HR-97, Volume SN-352)
  - Scrapbook* #37 (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-353)
  - Advertising Material, 1930s? (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-354)
    Sequence numbers 354-357 are a set of 4 packets. Sequence 354 and 355 are unlabeled, but as they are packaged similarly to 356 and 357, which are labeled, these appear to be advertising/marketing material developed by the Wendell P. Colton Company.
  - Advertising Material, 1930s? (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-355)
  - Advertising Material, 1933 (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-356)
  - Advertising Material, 1932 (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-357)
  - Scrapbook* #39 (Offsite-box HR-98, Volume SN-358)
  - Progress schedules (Offsite-box HR-99, Volume SN-359)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-99, Volume SN-360)
  - Scrapbook* #38 (Offsite-box HR-99, Volume SN-361)
  - Scrapbook* #36 (Offsite-box HR-100, Volume SN-362)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-100, Volume SN-363)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-100, Volume SN-364)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-101, Volume SN-365)
  - Scrapbook* #33 (Offsite-box HR-101, Volume SN-366)
  - Scrapbook* (Offsite-box HR-102, Volume SN-367)
  - Scrapbook (Offsite-box HR-104, Volume SN-367.1)
  - Scrapbook, 1940s (Offsite-box HR-104, Volume SN-367.2)
  - Scrapbook. Newspaper advertising, 1924-1943 (Offsite-box HR-104, Volume SN-367.3)
  - Scrapbook (Advertising?) (Offsite-box HR-102, Volume SN-368)
  - Scrapbook. SS Albany, Hendrick Hudson, Mary Powell, Robert Fulton, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box HR-103, Volume SN-369)
  - Scrapbook. Advertising, 1916-circa 1922 (Offsite-box HR-103, Volume SN-370)
  - Scrapbook. (Advertising?) (Offsite-box HR-104, Volume SN-371)